Guide to Janice C. Neal papers, 1962-1964.
Fenimore Art Museum
Janice C. Neal papers, 1962-1964.
.50 cu. ft.
Neal, Janice C., 1902-1966.
Fenimore Art Museum Research Library 80 Lake Road Cooperstown, NY 13326
Coll. No. 468
Call Numbers: 398 N341; Sp.Coll. 398 N341
Gift; Alma Slawson, Oneonta, NY; 1984; NM-33.84.
Acquisition Information
Coll. No. 468 is open for research according to the regulations of Fenimore Art Museum Library.
Janice Neal, child of Frank E Neal, 1869-1952 and Minnie E. Miller Neal, b. 1872, was a lifelong resident of Oneonta, Otsego County, NY. She studied at the State University of New York in Albany, became a public school teacher in Unadilla, Otsego County, NY, and was a member of several historical organizations. A pamphlet of her writing, “Otsego County Bits and Pieces,” was published posthumously.
Biography/History
Neal, Janice C., 1902-1966.; Peacox, Earle F., 1907-1982.; Neal family.; Oneonta (Otsego County, N.Y.); correspondence; genealogies (histories); Oneonta (N.Y.)--Family and personal papers.; $aOneonta (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.
Contains 67 personal letters and 5 work books of genealogical notes. The bulk of the letters (45 in all) are written by Janice Neal to “Cousin Blanche” (possibly Mrs. Fred Wood) between 1961-1961. Neal writes of her activities at school, in organizations, and at church, of friends, nature, local news, and of the books she is reading and the genealogical research she is doing.
Scope and Contents
Also included are 21 letters to Neal from Earle F. Peacox, Webster, Montgomery County, NY. These letters focus primarily on genealogical research. The 5 genealogical work books include handwritten notes on families, and cemetery and church records and other sources of documentary evidence. Family names include: Miller, deGraff, Bush, and Stancil/Stansell.
Neal is a very good letter writer.
- No. 468/1.1 Correspondence - to Blanche., 1961 - 1962
- No. 468/1.2 Correspondence - to Blanche., 1963-1964, n.d.
- No. 468/1.3 Correspondence - from Blanche., 1963
- No. 468/1.4 Correspondence - from Earle Peacox., 1961 - 1968
- No. 468/1.5 Misc. correspondence and ephemera.
- No. 468/1.6 Work book - Bush/Miller geneaologies., n.d.
- No. 468/1.7 Work book - Miller/Casler/deGraff/Stancel/Young/Smith/Freeman/Roof geneaologies., n.d.
- No. 468/1.8 Work book - "Records Church & Cemetery Halls Snells Riffenbergs.", n.d.
- No. 468/1.9 Work book - Miller/Bush/Stansel geneaologies incl. notes on Otsego and Schoharie county cemeteries.
- No. 468/1.10 Work book- Stansell/Featherly geneaologiews, incl. correspondence from Earle Peacox., 1963